Bala Kannan

LIFE means Learn Intelligence From Events

infobalacbe@gmail.com

+91-814-708-8005

Achievements and Accolades:

As Entrepreneur:

Cloud Based Entertainment Company: Indianstage.in (funded)

Orchestration and Security : bworks.in (POC Stage)

As Employee:

DEVOPS, Release and Program Management, Data Security:

Serus, enStage, Playroom (Disney), Sprinklr,

Datacenter, Cloud Migration and Orchestration at :

Indianstage, Reliance Petroleum, Jamcracker, Synovate and enStage.

Summary

Bala Kannan is a cloud computing visionary, technology innovator, and agent of change. Bala's industry experience includes tenures as Architect, **Co-Founder of successful Cloud and IT Infrastructure** based private software companies, and guiding teams to improve solution by adopting right technology for niche problems. Bala has added value to startup's by transforming companies from traditional to innovative technologies, and moving them to lucrative exits that benefited investors, employees, and customers. Know for his quick delivery and excellent planning. Bala provides core leadership to drive productive use of resources, as well as strategic leadership to drive true innovation within ever-changing technology markets. This ability to offer a hybrid leadership approach is a key point of value to Bala clients as he contributes to their projects' and companies success

As a Entrepreneur: Built a cloud based entertainment company (indianstage.in), assisted **in getting successfully funded**, also started a cloud based orchestration company (bworks.in) which help Enterprises to solve bigger technology problems and try to invent solutions. As a Technology

Enthusiast: Senior Technical Enthusiast have experience in setting up DEV-OPS and Continuous Delivery Model along with Orchestration, Cloud Migration, across IDC and Cloud Data-centers for Enterprises and Start-ups. Worked upon complex industry problems and helped corporate, Enterprise and their clients in the designing Solutions for cloud, security defined strategies in and in product's life cycle management so that they play a pivotal role from a software engineering and technology perspective. Designed and executed Innovative and Customised solutions which will help business people to overcome the Release Management Stress. Data security and Cloud Migrations are something Specialist designed a generic solution especially for services delivered over the cloud.

Experience

Cloud Datacenter Architect and Seasonal Entrepreneur at Bworks

March 2010 - Present (4 years 10 months)

Senior Cloud Enthusiast Worked with Solution Architects and Clients to choose suitable cloud providers, Technology Stack and solutions based on the requirement and domain. Hand hold stable Release Management and Delivery Process on Hybrid Environments. Information and Data Security measures has to be at every step of solution due to growing demand for data, so we have implemented best security practices as part of every release.

1 recommendation available upon request

Continuous Delivery at Playdom (Disney Interactive Studios)

October 2011 - November 2012 (1 year 2 months)

As a DEVOPS Lead providing core leadership in supporting continuous releases cloud strategy, architecture, and implementation. was Member of the executive team, providing strategic guidance for the company. Additionally, providing key thought leadership activities including keynote presentations at most major cloud computing conferences.

Senior Application and DataCenter Manager at Serus Corporation

May 2010 - February 2012 (1 year 10 months)

IT and Dev OPS (SCM) Manager.

Sr.System Administration at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

March 2007 - April 2011 (4 years 2 months)

7 recommendations available upon request

Sr.System Administrator at Jamcracker

March 2007 - April 2010 (3 years 2 months)

Handled End to End IT-Operations offshore activities, team building, troubleshooting Cloud Implementation(public and Private) and Build and Release Management.

5 recommendations available upon request

Datacenter System administrator at Synovate

2006 - 2007 (1 year)

Datacenter Manager at Reliance Petroleoum

2003 - 2004 (1 year)

Started my career here, along with all the racks, cables and technology we built the data-center to support

Petroleum business. Learnt Linux, Networking, extensive troubleshooting Support Scalability for the business which grew 2 folds month on month. Explored opportunity to automate, and expand dynamically.

Volunteer Experience

Contributor at Samarthan School for Blind

May 2011 - Present (3 years 8 months)

Languages

Tamil English

(Full professional proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Data Center, Agile Methodologies Amazon Web Services (AWS), Cloud Computing, IaaS, Linux, Virtualisation, Web Services, ERP, Unix, IT Management, Oracle, MySQL, Requirements Analysis, Enterprise Software, Software Configuration Management, Start-ups, Information Security, IT Outsourcing, OpenStack, Docker, Datacenter Orchestration

Release Management, Product Management, Private Equity Funding, Entrepreneurship

Education

Bharathiar University

BS, Computer Technology, 2000 - 2003

Activities and Societies: Inter College Drama's

Stanes Higher Secondary School

HSC, Science, 1998 - 2000

Activities and Societies: Stage Play's, Poem Writing and Orator

Recomendations

13 recomendations

"Reliable, methodical and trusted coupled with enthusiasm and solid knowledge of systems and IT Management. Those were my first and lasting impressions of Bala. He was able to quickly take control of all of our hosted infrastructure and develop systems and methods to provide SLA guarantees for mission critical hosted ERP grade applications. What was great about Bala was not just technical knowledge but understanding of business of infrastructure, economics of SaaS and Cloud computing. I would hire him in a heartbeat again."

- Shailley Singh, Director, Serus, managed Bala indirectly at Serus

"Bala in simple is a highly energetic and committed person any one would like to have in the team. Would recommend him to any future employer."

— Ramakrishna Nutulapati (RK), *Sr Manager QA*, *Jamcracker*, managed Bala indirectly at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

"Bala is a terrific person and a core technical professional. His level of expertise in his field of work is exemplary. Bala is always about 'service with a smile'. No matter what, his attitude is always pleasant and he is always forthcoming. Bala is a pleasure to work with and I look forward to working with him again in the future again."

— **Aruna Ramabadran**, *Lead - Documentation*, *Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd*, worked with Bala at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

"Coming from windows world, Bala transformed into Linux world easily. Shows keen interest in learning new every day which has opened doors into build and deployments, version control systems. Committed persons help any team or company, Bala is one of them. Wish him all the best."

— **Kiran Kumar Bysani**, *Software Configuration Management Specialist*, *Jamcracker*, managed Bala at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

"Bala is a dedicated, hardworking professional. A real asset to any organisation. During my association with JC, I have worked closely with Bala and found him to be technically competent and very reliable."

— **Rekha R**, *Human Resource Manager*, *Jamcracker*, managed Bala indirectly at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

"I have had the pleasure of working with Bala for the past 3+ yr and have found I can count on his committment to high quality service and support. He has been instrumental in provide support to our team consistently to meet the project deadlines. He was was able to quickly understand issues/problems and provide effective action to bring the situation under controll."

— **Kamlesh Vyas**, *Sr. Architect, Jamcracker*, managed Bala indirectly at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

"Bala is hardworking with a positive attitude. He is approachable, friendly and always willing to work with everyone in the team."

— **Shivani Jagia**, *Sr SCM*, *Jamcracker*, worked directly with Bala at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

"A really good System Administrator. He has good technical knowledge for his job. His attitude towards the work and his colleagues are really admirable."

— **Prasad P Nair**, *Senior Technical Lead*, *Jamcracker*, *Inc*., worked with Bala at Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

"Bala is good self motivated technical person and also I have been worked with him on lot of implementations which has been executed successfully."

- Aravind Vannu, Tech Lead, Jamcracker, worked directly with Bala at Jamcracker

"Bala is a hard working and sincere person on whom one can depend. He has good grasp of systems administration activities on Windows, UNIX and Networking. He's always eager to learn new things. He understands and works out anything to objectives and hence he tries different approaches to solve any problem at hand. Good friend, supporting person... always willing and ready to help."

— Harcharan Mittu, Manager - IT Operations, Jamcracker Software Technologies Pvt Ltd, managed Bala at Jamcracker

"I ahve known Bala for the past 2+years and it has been a pleasure working with him. The striking observation about Bala is his ability to grasp a given situation and come up with a viable solution. His obvious domain expertise, his quest to learn constantly and his friendly demeanor makes him one of our popular team members. Bala has the ability to scale greater heights and the attitude to reach there quickly."

- Lux Rao, Marketing Director - Global Channels, Jamcracker Inc, managed Bala indirectly at Jamcracker

"When I was Jamcracker, I worked with Bala on several occasions. Bala is a hardworking, smart sys admin. The network/sys team was continuously under heavy pressure to deliver to several stakeholders and Bala was in the center of the storm delivery calmly and efficiently. He is very knowledgeable, approachable, affable (a lot of good 'ables' about Bala). People like Bala make the difference in an organization - whether its crunch time or just simply to hang out!"

- Baskar Ethirajan, Product Manager, Jamcracker, worked with Bala at Jamcracker

"He's always interested in taking up new tasks. Tries to learn different things on his own. Talented and very good team player."

— **Vinoth K G**, *Prinicipal Member of Technical Team*, *Jamcracker Software technologies pvt ltd*, worked with Bala at Jamcracker

Contact Bala on LinkedIn